<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Kat Morgan</title><link>https://blog.usrbinkat.io/en/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Kat Morgan</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.usrbinkat.io/en/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🔧 Golang installation and management in 2025 🚀</title><link>https://blog.usrbinkat.io/en/blog/golang-mise-on-macos-and-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.usrbinkat.io/en/blog/golang-mise-on-macos-and-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>Starting new projects can be overwhelming, especially when switching to long-forgotten or even new emerging skillsets, languages, and tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In recent weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up new greenfield Go projects, and I realized it has been almost 4 years since I last started a new project in this language. Given the velocity of the developer tooling ecosystem, it felt prudent to research the latest trends and best practices to re-skill with the advantage of the latest tools and techniques.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Universal Object Reference: The Hitchhikers Guide to Baking the Omniverse</title><link>https://blog.usrbinkat.io/en/blog/universal-object-reference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.usrbinkat.io/en/blog/universal-object-reference/</guid><description>&lt;p>Imagine stepping into an infinite kitchen, where every conceivable ingredient is at your fingertips. Flour, water, butter, spices—and even more abstract ingredients like time, entropy, and observation—are neatly arranged, waiting to be transformed. This kitchen is more than a metaphor; it’s a mental playground where the Universal Object Reference (UOR) acts as your recipe book, guiding you through the alchemy of combining objects to fundamentally understand and interact with the universe itself. The beauty of this kitchen lies not just in its endless ingredients but in the intricate web of interactions that form when objects observe each other, shaping the very reality they inhabit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kubernetes VMware Replacement: Building Simplicity with Modern Technology</title><link>https://blog.usrbinkat.io/en/blog/k8s-bare-metal-vmware-replacement/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.usrbinkat.io/en/blog/k8s-bare-metal-vmware-replacement/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://jurassicpark.fandom.com/wiki/Quote:Ian_Malcolm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&amp;hellip;your scientists were so preoccupied with whether or not they could, they didn&amp;rsquo;t stop to think if they should.&lt;/a>
&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br>
— &lt;cite>Dr. Ian Malcolm (Jeff Goldblum) from Jurassic Park&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/cite>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Building simple technology is one of the most challenging endeavors in our industry. Technology evolution often follows cyclical patterns, with today&amp;rsquo;s innovations echoing architectural decisions of the past—a tradition stretching back to the mid-century pioneers of operating systems and compiler design. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore Kubernetes as a path toward simplification getting too lost in the details for this article.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://blog.usrbinkat.io/en/blog/windows11-cloud-devops-developer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.usrbinkat.io/en/blog/windows11-cloud-devops-developer/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://bit.ly/the-only-fear-is-fear-itself" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The only thing we have to fear is fear itself.&lt;/a>
&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br>
— &lt;cite>Franklin Delanor Roosevelt &lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/cite>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trying new things and challenging old beliefs is scary sometimes, but it’s also a great way to grow. While it’s fresh on my mind, I decided to document and share my initial setup of WSL Ubuntu, along with some creature comforts and personal preferences. Feel free to peruse each section and try out anything you like in your own system or VM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🎈1yr Pulumi Anniversary!🎊</title><link>https://blog.usrbinkat.io/en/blog/one-year-of-pulumi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.usrbinkat.io/en/blog/one-year-of-pulumi/</guid><description>&lt;p>From learning to code, content engineering, the rise of AI, Platform Engineering and beyond. So much learning, teaching, and creating. I want to talk about it so let&amp;rsquo;s dive in!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The art of teaching is the art of assisting discovery&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br>
— &lt;cite>Mark Van Dore &lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/cite>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>